<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="124" moduleid="5923" modulename="book" contextid="19811">
  <book id="124">
    <name>Conclusion</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;conclusion&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1462547347</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1462547347</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="932">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Review of common LD descriptors</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Review of common LD descriptors&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This module examined current trends and issues in defining LD. We started by examining the language we use to describe individuals with learning challenges. As a reminder, some of these descriptors include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning differences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning difficulties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning challenges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning disorders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two guiding questions helped to clarify what it means to have LD as opposed to a learning difficulty, difference, or challenge. Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to review our two guiding questions.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462547370</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="933">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Review of guiding question #1</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Review of guiding question #1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guiding question number one asked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What are six consensus statements that help us understand the definition of LD?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this question we examined six consensus statements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The concept of LD is valid and is supported by strong converging evidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LD are neurologically based and intrinsic to the individual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individuals with LD show intra-individual differences in skills and abilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LD persist across the life span.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LD may occur in combination with other disabling conditions, but they are not due to other conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LD are evident across ethnic, cultural, language, and economic groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These six consensus statements are important because they represent what is agreed upon in the field of LD. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462547395</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="934">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Review of guiding question #2</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Review of guiding question #2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guiding question number two asked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What are examples from your work with adults with LD that are associated with the six consensus statements?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question led us to explore your experiences in order to help make the definition of LD more meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also explored two models for diagnosing individuals as having LD that are currently allowable by federal special education legislation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IQ-Achievement discrepancy model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Response to Intervention (RtI) model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to share your reflections about what you learned in this module.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462547418</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="935">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Share your thoughts about the concepts and ideas presented in Definitions of Learning Disabilities</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Share your thoughts about the concepts and ideas presented in Definitions of Learning Disabilities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To wrap up, please take a moment to review the working definition of LD that you wrote at the beginning of this module, as well as your previous thoughts on how the six consensus statements may affect your work with adults having diagnosed or undiagnosed LD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, reflect on what you have learned and how you plan to use the information in your work with adults by answering the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What additional insight do you now have about what it means for an individual to have LD?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How might the information you learned in this module affect your work with adults?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please share your reflections in the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/discussion/online-course-learning-achieve-definitions-learning-disabilities" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Disabilities in Adult Education Group&lt;/a&gt; before moving on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have finished posting your reflections, click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to continue.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462547696</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="936">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Participate in the forum discussions</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Participate in the forum discussions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on completing Learning to Achieve’s &lt;i&gt;Definitions of Learning Disabilities&lt;/i&gt;&lt;em&gt;!&lt;/em&gt; We encourage you to stay involved in the LINCS Community and the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/group/disabilities-adult-education" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Disabilities in Adult Education Group&lt;/a&gt; as you strive to identify and understand LD. We encourage you to discuss and apply your newly acquired knowledge and learn about others' experiences in teaching adults with LD.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462557457</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="937">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Complete the evaluation and print your certificate</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Complete the evaluation and print your certificate&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concludes the &lt;i&gt;Definitions of Learning Disabilities&lt;/i&gt; course. We would like to thank the individuals and organizations who generously contributed to the design and development of this course:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINCS Regional Professional Development Center, Region 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Center for Literacy, Education &amp;amp; Employment at the University of Tennessee, Knoxville staff Aaron Kohring, Duren Thompson, and Margy Ragsdale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;National Institute for Literacy independent panel of experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;So that we can maintain the quality of our courses, we ask that you take a moment to complete the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt; &lt;/b&gt;course evaluation&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;. Your feedback will ensure our courses meet your needs for professional development. Thank you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin-bottom: 30px; margin-top: 30px;" class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 1em; line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Access and Print Your Certificate Anytime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on completing this LINCS Learning to Achieve course, Definitions of Learning Disabilties. To obtain your completion certificate, simply close this window and return to the course homepage. You will find a link for the completion certificate under the Course Conclusion and Resources section header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Literacy Information and Communication System (LINCS) Learning to Achieve course was developed by Manhattan Strategy Group, LLC for the U.S. Department of Education, Office of Career, Technical, and Adult Education under Contract No. ED-VAE-14-C-0123. The opinions expressed herein do not necessarily represent the positions or policies of the U.S. Department of Education, and no official endorsement by the U.S. Department of Education should be inferred. This course is in the public domain and may be used without permission.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469562048</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>