<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="121" moduleid="5920" modulename="book" contextid="19808">
  <book id="121">
    <name>Consensus Statement #6</name>
    <intro>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;section 6&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1462397687</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1462397765</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="916">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>LD occur in all population groups</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;LD occur in all population groups&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s move on to consensus statement #6. “&lt;b&gt;LD are evident across ethnic, cultural, language, and economic groups&lt;/b&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been controversy over the view that LD are a “social construction” – a way of labeling individuals who are just different learners. However, research shows that LD occur in all cultural and economic groups in countries across the world. This reinforces the first point, that LD are real. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/78652364_cropped.jpg" width="350" height="357" alt="Photo of a diverse group of people, various ages and ethnicities." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462461223</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="917">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Lack of appropriate tests for LD remain a concern in the U.S.</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Lack of appropriate tests for LD remain a concern in the U.S.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, there is a concern that identification procedures are culturally biased and that in K-12 education, minority groups with LD have historically been overrepresented. For example, special education research tells us that from ages 6 through 21, American Indian/Alaskan Native students and African-American students with LD are overrepresented in special education (1.50 times and 1.31 times, respectively) and white non-Hispanic students are underrepresented (0.88 times as likely to be served for LD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, one issue in LD identification in the United States is the lack of culturally and linguistically appropriate tests, testing procedures and teacher recommendations. Despite these concerns, however, the field reached consensus that LD are not unique to any one culture; they exist across cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Globe_hands.jpg" width="550" height="426" alt="A globe with four pairs of hands arranged in a circle around it" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462461343</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="918">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Review of the six consensus statements</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Review of the six consensus statements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have examined each of the six consensus statements that help in understanding how experts in the field have defined LD, and have thus addressed our first guiding question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are &lt;b&gt;six consensus statements&lt;/b&gt; that help us understand the definition of LD?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a few moments to review the six statements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The concept of LD is valid and is supported by strong converging evidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LD are neurologically based and intrinsic to the individual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individuals with LD show intra-individual differences in skills and abilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LD persist across the life span.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LD may occur in combination with other disabling conditions, but they are not due to other conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LD are evident across ethnic, cultural, language, and economic groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s move on to consider this information while addressing our other guiding question for this lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;Continue on to Guiding Question #2, Introduction and Activities&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462557329</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>